(綱手)これは まさか…。
This…can't be.
What is happening?!
(ヒルゼン)なんたることじゃ。
＜綱手 : その年➡
Right around then,
the young shinobi
who just became genin,
下忍になったばかりの
若い忍たちは➡
made their way to a village
that had lost their jonin.
里の上忍たちが
消息を絶ってしまった村へと➡
向かっていた。
Amongst them was
the Child of Prophecy…Naruto.
その中に
予言の子 ナルトの姿もあった＞
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero
The Search Mission
(ミナト)何があったんだい？
What happened?
知っていることがあったら
なんでもいい 話してほしい。
If there's something that you know,
please tell me…whatever it is.
(イロハ)すみません
イズモさん コテツさんが➡
I'm sorry.
Izumo and Kotetsu
suddenly disappeared
突然 消えてしまったので➡
逃げてくるのが精いっぱいで。
and I just got out of there
as fast as I could…
正直 どうやって➡
To be honest, I don't even
remember how I made it here.
戻ってきたのかさえ記憶がなくて。
(ミナト)そうだね
つらい思いをさせてしまったね。
I understand.
I'm sorry to put you
through all that.
ささいなことでもかまわない。
But even if you remember
something minor, please tell me.
もし 何か思い出したら
教えてほしい。
アゲハ… アゲハ蝶。
Ageha…
An Ageha butterfly…
(綱手)おそらく
シノビアゲハのことだろう。
He's probably talking about
the Shinobi Ageha…
今の季節 あの里の近くの森なら
珍しくはない。
During this season,
it's not unusual to see them
in the forest near that village.
Is it a poisonous butterfly?
その蝶に 何か毒性は…。
いや その鱗粉には
チャクラの流れを促す効果があり➡
No.
Its powdery scales
stimulate chakra flow
兵糧丸の材料にも
用いられるほどだ。
and it's even a main ingredient
in food pills.
《イズモとコテツが 手もなく
やられるとは思えないのだが…》
I can't believe Izumo and Kotetsu
were beaten so easily…
だいたい 揃ったようだね。
Looks like we're all set.
(シカマル)まだ第七班が…。
No, Team 7 is still…
(カカシ)第七班 遅くなりました。
Sorry, Team 7 is late.
これで全員だね。 早速だけど
次の任務を説明しよう。
We're all here now.
I know it's sudden,
but let me go over the mission.
I hope its way more exciting
than looking for a lost cat.
(ナルト)迷い猫探しとかじゃなくて
もっと派手な任務がやりてえな。
今度のは 重要任務だよ。
This mission is very important.
ハハッ！
密命をおびて村へおもむいた
三班の忍が➡
Three teams of shinobi that were
dispatched on secret missions
皆 一斉に消息をたってしまった。
have all gone missing.
諸君の任務は
行方不明者の探索だ。
Your mission is to
search and find them.
ウッヒョ～！
Yahoo!
ただし 発見ししだい
木ノ葉隠れへの連絡を取るように。
However, you are to contact
the Hidden Leaf
the moment they are found.
勝手な救出活動は禁じる。
Any attempts at rescue
are forbidden.
なんで？
Why?!
選ばれたメンバーを見りゃ➡
Considering who's been chosen,
おのずから その答えは
わかりそうなもんだろう。
the answer should be
pretty obvious to everyone.
それは 俺たちが才能に満ち溢れた
エリート忍者だからか？
Is it because we're all elite ninja
overflowing with talent?!
行方不明になった忍たちは
ほとんど手練の上忍たち。
Nearly all the shinobi who
went missing are capable jonin…
ところが 里へ戻ることが
できたのは下忍１人だ。
But the only one who was able to
make it back to the village,
was a genin.
推測されるのは 経験とか年齢が➡
So it could mean, experience
and maturity are being targeted.
関係しているかもしれない
ってことだ。
う～ん… というと？
Which means?
つまり
俺たちが下忍になったばっかの➡
In other words, we were picked
because we're newbies
下っ端だから選ばれたのさ。
who just became genin.
まぁ そうも言えるね。
Well, you could put it that way…
え～ そうなのか。
What?
Is that all?
《ナルト… きっとキミなら…》
Naruto, you will most likely
be the one who—
みんな 止まれ！
Everyone, stop!
何だ？ 何だ？
What is it?
Isn't our target village
further ahead?
目的の村は もう少し先だろう？
Look.
(サスケ)あれだ。
ん？
あれは…。
(サクラ)シノビアゲハ？
What's that?
Shinobi Ageha?
All right! I'm gonna go catch 'em!
よ～し
俺がとっ捕まえてやる！
Hey! You!
あっ こら！
その必要はないけどね。
That's really not necessary…
連れ戻す。
そうなの？
I'll bring him back!
Oh really?
も～。
やれやれ…。
Come on!
Oh boy…
はっ！
八卦盤掌。
Eight Trigrams Grid Palm!
《これは…》
This is…
うう…。
ハァ ハァ…。
カカシ先生!?
Kakashi Sensei!
ナルト！ すぐ戻れ。
あ～！
Naruto! Get back here right now!
も～ 何なんだよ！
今 捕まえるとこだったのに！
What the hell?
I almost had it!
任務中だ。 勝手に動くな。
なんだと！
Don't go off on your own
during a mission.
What did you just say?
お前に命令される筋合いは ねえ！
I don't take orders from you!
What? This isn't an order!
ああ!? 命令じゃない。
忍らしくしろと言ってるだけだ！
I'm telling you to act
more like a shinobi!
Going off on your own
puts others in—
１人の勝手な行動が仲間を…。
Sasuke!
Kakashi Sensei's in trouble!
(サクラ)サスケ君！ カカシ先生が大変！
– What happened?
– Kakashi Sensei's…
どうした？
カカシ先生が…。
気づいたときには もう…。
When I noticed, he…
地中に引きずり込まれたか…。
そんな！
He was dragged underground, huh?
No way!
(アスマ)これは… うっ…。
What—!
うう…。
アスマ!?
Asuma!
クソッ！ やられた…。
Damn it…
They got him.
(チョウジ)何？ どうなっちゃったの？
What? What happened?
(いの)アスマ先生は どこ？
いや… わからねえ。
Where's Asuma Sensei?
I-I don't know…
《ヒナタ : これは…
この感じは チャクラ!?》
Is this…
…sensation, chakra?!
(キバ)何があったんだ？ 赤丸！
What happened, Akamaru?!
(シノ)赤丸が鳴いたのは
何かあったからではない。
Akamaru's barking not because of
something happening.
It's because
he lost track of Kurenai Sensei
むしろ 紅先生のあるべき姿が
なくなったからだ。
who should be present.
《ネジ : なんだ これは…。
What is this?
Byakugan!
白眼！》
(ネジ)地面の下に チャクラの流れが…。
There's a current of chakra
underground…
いったい どこから…。
Where is it coming from?
(テンテン)ネジ！ どこへ!?
調べたいことがある！
Neji! Where are you going?
I want to check something!
Stay with Guy!
ガイと 一緒にいてくれ。
(ガイ)うぐっ…。
(リー)ガイ先生！
Guy Sensei!
胸が苦しいんですか!?
Does your chest hurt?!
何のこれしき… 根性で！
It's nothing that
a little perseverance can't…
うっ！
ガイ先生！
Guy Sensei!
Don't push yourself!
無理しちゃ ダメです！
今 冷たい水をくんできます！
I'll go get some water.
テンテン ガイ先生を頼みましたよ。
ええ。
Tenten, stay and watch Guy Sensei.
All right!
何があった。
What happened?
Guy Sensei felt sick and…
ガイ先生の具合が悪くなって。
ガイ先生は!?
Where's Guy Sensei?!
黒いツタのようなものが
生えてきて…。
Black vine-like things sprang up,
ガイ先生に巻きついて
地面の中へ…。
wrapped around Sensei,
and pulled him underground.
What?
(リー)なんですって!?
《チャクラの流れが消えている…》
The current of chakra is gone.
お～い。
Hey!
おそらく カカシは敵の手に落ちた。
Kakashi Sensei is probably
in enemy hands.
私たち いったいどうすれば…。
What are we supposed to do?
What else is there to do?!
そんなの決まってんだろ！
なんとしても捜しだして➡
We're gonna find him no matter what
and get him back!
連れ戻すってばよ！
ったく…。
Damn it.
ぜってぇ 諦めねえ!!
I'm never giving up!
Hey, what are we going to do?
どうするのよ… ねぇ。
ねぇ どうなっちゃうのよ。
What's going to happen?
とりあえず 他の班と連絡取って➡
First, we should contact
the other teams,
そのあと 火影様の命令どおり➡
then contact the Leaf Village
like Lord Hokage ordered, right?
木ノ葉隠れの里へ
連絡しなきゃ。 だろ？
うん。
待てよ 動くな！
Wait.
Don't move!
え？
What?
Damn it.
まったく 四代目が➡
What the Fourth Hokage feared
would happen just happened…
危惧していたとおりのことが
起こっちまうとはな。
え？
他の班長たちにも➡
Huh?!
It's probably safe to assume that
同じようなことが起こったとみて
まず間違いねえ。
the same thing has happened
to the other team captains.
他の班もって…。
僕たちだけじゃなくて➡
The other teams?
So it's not only us…
But Sasuke and Kiba and…
サスケたちとか キバたちとか➡
みんな 取り残されちゃった
ってこと？
Everyone's been left behind?
ああ。 なかでもカカシ班は➡
Yeah…
I just hope Kakashi's team isn't
arguing with each other right now…
今ごろ
もめてなきゃいいんだが…。
めんどくせえやつがいるからな。
Since they have someone
who can be a real drag.
この～っ！
待て！ ウスラトンカチ！
Why you—!
Wait, you loser!
言ったはずだ！ 俺は諦めねえ！
I already told you!
I'm not giving up!
でも どこ行くつもり!?
But where are you going?
Well, I don't know, but…
そりゃ… わかんねえけどさ。
Are you really the son of
the Fourth Hokage?
お前 ほんとに
四代目火影の息子か？
なんだと!?
四代目火影が➡
What did you say?!
Do you really think the Hokage
would send us out
何も手を打たずに
送り出したと思うか？
without making any
preventive measures beforehand?
えっ!?
あの時➡
I saw the Hokage
pass out special kunai
火影が 班長たちに
特製のクナイを渡すのを見た。
to the captains, back then.
特製クナイ？
ああ。
Special kunai?
Yeah…
時空間忍術で飛び回るとき
目印にするやつだ。
The one he marks when he uses
the Transportation Ninjutsu
to teleport.
その目印があれば どこにいても
すぐ駆けつけられる。
As long as the mark is there,
he can track anyone, anywhere.
時空間忍術？
Transportation Ninjutsu?
口寄せの術はわかるな？
You know what
the Summoning Jutsu is, right?
Uh…yeah!
おう！
あの術の一種だと思え。
Think of it as
a type of that jutsu.
特製クナイが目印となり➡
The special kunai is the target
どんなに
遠くに離れていようとも➡
and no matter
how far away you are…
一瞬にして
クナイのもとへ飛ぶことができる。
you can transport to the kunai
in an instant…
今は 四代目火影だけが
使える術だ。
Lord Fourth is the only one
who can use that jutsu right now.
そうか～
やっぱ すげえな 父ちゃん。
I see. I gotta admit…
My Dad's pretty awesome!
待って！
あの～ それがダメみたい。
Wait!
I don't think…
that's going to happen.
え？
え～ それって…。
Huh? That's…
さっきの場所に落ちてたの。
I found it at the spot right now.
最悪の状況だ。
This is the worst situation
we can be in…
I think I can visualize Lee making
a big fuss over Guy Sensei.
リーのやつも
ガイ先生 ガイ先生って➡
大騒ぎしてるのが
目に見えるようだぜ。
ガイ先生！ ガイ先生！ ガイ先生！
Guy Sensei! Guy Sensei!
ガイ先生!!
待って リー！
Wait, Lee!
Calm down!
冷静になるんだ。
そんなこと僕には無理です。
That's impossible for me!
あなたたちは ガイ先生の命より➡
Is the Shinobi Code more important
to you two than Guy Sensei's life?!
掟が大事なんですか！
勘違いするな！
Don't get the wrong idea!
この～ わからずや!!
You blockhead!
うっ… ガイ せ ん せ い！
Guy…Sensei.
何をするんです！
いいから聞け！
What are you doing?
Just listen!
ガイが行方不明になる直前
地中に奇妙なチャクラが流れていた。
Just before Guy went missing,
there was an unusual current
of chakra underground.
えっ 白眼で見えてたんですか？
You saw it with your Byakugan?
ああ。 今は消えてしまったがな。
Yeah. But it's disappeared now.
そこで 他の班の状況も
確認したい。
So, I'd like to check in on
the status of the other teams.
今は 他の班との合流が最優先だ。
Linking up with the other teams
is our priority right now.
そこで キーとなるのが紅班だ。
どういうこと？
So, the key players
will be Kurenai's team.
How so?
(シカマル)キバの嗅覚
ヒナタの白眼 シノの奇壊蟲。
Kiba's sense of smell,
Hinata's Byakugan and
Shino's Parasitic Insects…
やつらの感知能力があれば➡
With their sensory skills,
it will be easy to find the current
locations of the other three teams.
他の３班の現在地を
突きとめるのは容易。
それに それぞれの班長が
連れ去られたところも➡
And they can probably find
the location where
the team captains are being held.
突きとめることが
できるかもしれねぇ。
そうね ヘタに動くより
そのほうが手っ取り早いかも。
You're right!
That would make it way faster than
just proceeding blindly.
こういうときは
パニックと思考停止が➡
In situations like this,
panic and proceeding without
thinking is our worst enemy.
いちばん厄介だからな。
全員に仕事をつくる。
It makes more work for everybody.
だから 紅班と合流するまで➡
So until we join up
with Kurenai's team…
待ちだ。
…we'll just sit tight.
チョウジのやつ
昨日 焼き肉 食ったな。
Choji must've had
barbeque last night…
– Kiba!
キバ！
キバ君！
どうだ？
– How is it going?
– Hey!
おう アスマ班はあっちの方角にいる。
Asuma's team is over that way.
あいつら ピクリとも動かねえ。
Those guys aren't moving at all.
俺たちが 捜すのをわかってんだ。
They know we're looking for them.
余裕こいて 休んでやがるぜ。
They're just sitting back
and resting.
In any case, let's join up
with Shikamaru quickly.
(シノ)とにかく
一刻も早く シカマルと合流しよう。
そして やつの考えを
他の班の者たちに伝え➡
Then we'll pass on his ideas
to the other teams,
意思の統一を図る。 なぜなら➡
and come up with a unified plan.
That's because I have a feeling
考えなしで突っ走るやつに
心当たりがあるからだ。
there's someone who's going to
act without thinking through things…
そのためにも 私たちの能力が
必要になってくる。
And that's where
our abilities come in.
そういうこと！
シカマルご自慢の頭脳も➡
Exactly!
Shikamaru's acclaimed intellect
still needs us!
俺たち次第ってことよ！
(赤丸)ワン！
ナッハハハッ！
ワ～ン ワンワンワン！
コースから行くと
紅班は こっちにいるはずだ。
According to the plan,
Kurenai's team should be over here.
おう！
Right.
チッ！
Blood?!
(飛段)
すでに てめえは俺に呪われた。
I have already cursed you.
はぁ!?
Huh?
儀式の準備はできた。
Preparations for the ritual
are complete!
さあ 俺と一緒に➡
Now!
Let's experience
the ultimate pain together!
最高の痛みを味わおうぜ！
何だ？ こいつ。
What's with this guy?
He keeps talking about
curses and rituals?
呪いとか儀式とか…
危ねえやつだってばよ。
He's dangerous!
うっ。
ゲホッ アハハ。
うっ うぅ…。
ナルト！
– Naruto!
– Naruto?!
ハァ ハァ…。
Doesn't it hurt?
いてえだろ？
It's gonna be excruciating
so prepare yourself…
ムチャクチャいてえから
覚悟しろよ。
神の采配だ！
It's god's commandment!
Tremble in fear!
おそれおののけ！
本気で寝てるもんね。
He's fast asleep.
(シカマル)あいつは ああ見えて
寝起きはいい。
He may seem so,
but he wakes up sharp and alert.
それに 体力回復にもなるしな。
Besides,
it helps replenish his energy.
あんたは チョウジに甘い。
You're too easy on Choji.
フン いのは世知辛い。
And you're too tough.
やっぱその手はあるよな。
I knew something was up.
もう２～３手 先だと思ったが➡
I totally thought it would
happen later though.
素直に寝かしといちゃくれねえか。
I should have known they weren't
going to let us rest so easily.
It's coming!
(シカマル)来るぞ。
(小南)紙手裏剣。
Paper Shuriken!
Wind Style: Gale Palm!
(長門)風遁 烈風掌。
《クソ！
この紙吹雪から脱出しねえと》
Damn it… We have to
get out of this Paper Storm…
チョウジ！ ブチ破れるか!?
Choji! Can you break it apart?!
休養十分！
I've had enough rest!
倍化の術！
Expansion Jutsu!
肉弾戦車！ ゴロゴロゴロ…。
Human Boulder!
Roll, roll, roll, roll!
ゴロゴロゴロ…。
– Roll, roll, roll, roll!
– Water Style: Raging Waves!
ゴロゴロゴロ…。
(弥彦)水遁 水乱波！
あんたたちね！
You're the ones!
あんたたちが
アスマ先生をさらったのね？
You guys took Asuma Sensei, right?
そうでしょ！
アスマ先生を返せ！
Bring Asuma Sensei back!
Just who the hell…
誰なんだ てめえら。
…are you?
うっ…。
俺の呪いから逃げられると思うな。
Don't think you can
escape my curse!
忍の世界は呪われてんだ。
諦めな！
The shinobi world is cursed!
Just give up!
うっ… ぐっ…。
When the man in the strange cloak,
impaled himself
with his pointed scythe
皆様 お変わりございませんか？
Naruto felt an excruciating pain…
美空ひばりです。
今日も 皆さんに
喜んでいただける歌を➡
選んだつもりです。
Seems like this guy
is more than you can handl
どうぞ 最後まで
ごゆっくり ご覧ください。
今回のオープニングを飾るのは➡
美空ひばりさんが
一人二役で主演を務め➡